Judson James

https://judsonjames.com • judsonjames96@gmail.com

Full Stack Software Engineer with over three years of experience. Worked fulltime throughout college while obtaining his Computer Engineering degree. While working and managing course load, he also was recognized with Leadership Distinction in Public and Civic Engagement and a 3.4 GPA. Was previously laid off due to COVID, however, has been able to find work through connections and social networks. Currently looking for the right company and right people.

TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY

- Programming: JavaScript / TypeScript , Python, Go, Rust, Java, Shell, Rust, C/C++, C#, Dart,
- Technologies: Actix, Diesel, Django, DigitalOcean, Docker, Express, Falcon, Firebase, Flask, Flutter, GatsbyJS, GraphQL, Material UI, Mongo, Netlify, NextJS, Nginx, Node, PostgreSQL, React, Relay, REST, Rocket, Selenium
- DevOps: Docker / Kubernetes, Kanban / Agile, AWS, Git,
- Web application development using Python, JavaScript, Go, and Rust applications (Client, Server, or Static)
- Project Management and Software Life-Cycle management with GitHub, GitLab, and Jira
- Experienced with mono-repos that utilize multi-language and multi-platform solutions for clients
- Skilled in path-finding algorithms, robotic algorithms, and machine learning
- Strong verbal communication skills from tutoring and instructing students as well as client calls
- HIPAA Certified

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Trapp Technology Fully Remote from Lexington, KY

Aug 2020-Present

Software Developer: web/server applications

- Consistently work within a rapid paced Agile work environment to build web and server applications
- Collaborate and develop Go GraphQL server applications to be used by TypeScript React applications

52inc Columbia, SC

Jul 2019-Jul 2020

Software Developer: web/mobile/server applications

- Developed web and server applications using JavaScript and Python libraries
- Utilized custom webpack configurations for applications such as Microsoft Word and Google Docs
- Designed visually appealing frontends with Sketch and creating them in React-based frameworks
- Participated in code review for unit-testing and code linting

Center for Digital Humanities Columbia, SC

Dec 2018-May 2019

Software Developer: server applications

- Developed web applications using Diango and React and managed servers using Nginx/Gunicorn
- Built behavioral and unit tests for web applications throughout the department

Van Robotics, LLC Columbia, SC

May 2018-Nov 2018

Software Developer and Hardware Engineer

- Designed prototypes for Django web app that helps tutor fifth-grade students
- Designed the beta of the robotic hardware used to run the web app

University of South Carolina Student Success Center Columbia, SC Aug 2016–May 2019 Supplemental Instructor and Peer Leader

• Presented three weekly supplemental study sessions to develop concepts for students and enhance their understanding, hosting up to 50 students per session

• Developed lesson plans about computer science topics

EDUCATION

University of South Carolina Columbia, SC

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering May 2019

Graduated with Leadership Distinction in Public and Civic Engagement GPA: 3.4